As you create documents, you
will then need to save them in a
suitable location on your computer.
You may also need to take some
screen prints of folders to provide
evidence of work that you have done.
And obviously you can open
existing files that you have saved.
On a Mac, the first thing to do
with regards to saving your files.
So I have a sample document on the
screen in front of me, and I simply
need to go to the file and Save As.
And once I have selected that, I have
the name of the document and I'm quite
happy for it to be saved by that.
And then you have the location here.
So the Dropbox.
So what I'm going to do is I want
to save this document into my
documents folder, and I haven't got
a folder in there at the moment.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to
create a new folder and call that ITQ.
And then click Create and I can then save
that document inside of the ITQ folder.
And just as a, another point, the file
format there, it is saved as a docx
file, which is opened by any version
of Word other than very early versions.
If you wanted to save a document
that could be opened by very early
versions of Word you would need
to save it as a Word 97 to 2004.
Other alternatives are Word template.
Word 97 to 2004 template
and rich text format.
Sometimes if you're not sure what sort
of word processor that somebody may
have, if you saved it as rich text
format, that will be opened by any, so
it could be Open Office, Apache Office.
It will open any version
of rich text format.
So once I've done that I can select save
and that is then saved  in that folder.
Okay.
As you work through the IT course,
during your assessment, you will be
asked to provide screenshots to evidence
certain tasks that you have completed.
To take a screenshot on a Mac you
quite simply  need to find the folder
or the document that you wish to take
a screenshot of, make sure that it
is displayed clearly on the screen.
And there are two options.
You can take a snapshot
of  everything that's on the
screen at that moment in time.
Or you can specify a specific area.
To take a snapshot of exactly what's
on the screen at that time, you
can press the shift key and the
command key and hold those down
and then press the number three.
You will hear the sound of a
camera clicking, which indicates
that it has taken  the screenshot.
You can then go to the Word document.
In this example, I'm just using a
blank one, but when you're providing
screenshots, it will primarily
be in your assessment booklet.
So what I need to do then is hold
down the control key and press V.
And that will provide the screenshot.
So it's basically took a picture of
what was on the screen, and that as
now being entered into the document.
One of the benefits of organizing files
is that it makes it much easier to find
the files again when you need to continue
working with them, alternatively, you
can access files directly from a program.
In this demonstration, I'm just going to
give an example of how I can access files.
So I know I have files saved to
my ITQ folder on my documents,
and there's a letter in there.
And if I wanted to, I would
just double click and open it.
Another way that this can be
done is when in Word I can simply
bring up the Word documents and
then go to File and Open again.
And I navigate to the ITQ folder, double
click on that, and that will then open
the form document, as you can see.
Anytime I wish to save  that I don't need
to now Save As when I save that file, I
can just go to File and Save, or again, I
can press the command key and the S key.
Hold down command, press S.
And that will save  it.
I only need to Save As if I'm
changing the name of the document,
or I want to save another copy.